Good Morning, Church!
Good morning!
Viewers, Good Morning!
You may be seated, thank you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
I have done my own dance.
I would have shown it now, but I have been dancing since...
I was a viewer but now here I am.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Overflow Congregation
I am looking forward to see when you will allow me put on a suit;
when some of your spirits will allow me to put on a suit, when we will not fight.
That is why I had to dress this way.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
All I'm saying, "Allow me to wear a tie".
You will allow me one day to wear a tie.
This issue of faith.
Only faith pleases God.
It has given me so much concern.
People are not going through faith to talk to God anymore.
People imagine God hears them -
that is imagination.
To learn how to believe that God hears us when we pray is a much greater blessing
than healing and deliverance.
Just name them.
But how many of us today...?
You stand up to pray, "Lord Jesus", and you know He is hearing you, and you are hearing Him -
how many of you, how many of us today?
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Tell your neighbour:
“To learn how to believe that God hears us when we pray is a much greater blessing
than healing, deliverance and whatever you are waiting for.”
It is never proper to base faith on our improvement after prayer.
Why?
Because the prayer of faith can be repeated a thousand times.
"Jesus, give me bread" - Jesus may say, "Hold on. Not that I will not give you but hold on.
It is not the right time to give you".
That does not mean that your prayer is not answered.
"Jesus, I want to run."
"Hmm. This is not the right thing for you now to run."
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Jesus prayed that the cup be taken away from Him three times;
the same prayer He offered three times.
That does not mean His prayer was not answered.
That cup should be taken from Him - three times.
Let's quickly take a look at the Book of Matthew 26.
Take our reading from verse 36.
It says, “Then Jesus went with his disciples to a place called Gethsemane, and he said to them,
‘Sit here while I go over there and pray.’"
That said Jesus to His disciples.
“He took Peter and the two sons of Zebedee along with him, and he began to be sorrowful and troubled.
Then he said to them, ‘My soul is overwhelmed with sorrow to the point of death.
Stay here and keep watch with me.’
Going a little farther, he fell with his face to the ground and prayed,
‘My Father, if it is possible, may this cup be taken from me. Yet not as I will, but as you will.’
Then he returned to his disciples and found them sleeping.
‘Couldn’t you men keep watch with me for one hour?’ he asked Peter.
‘Watch and pray so that you will not fall into temptation. The spirit is willing, but the flesh is weak.’"
Verse 42:
“He went away a second time and prayed, ‘My Father, if it is not possible for this cup to be taken away
unless I drink it, may your will be done.’
When he came back, he again found them sleeping, because their eyes were heavy.
So he left them and went away once more and prayed the third time, saying the same thing.”
That is prayer of faith, saying the same thing, and then He returned to the disciples.
Take your time to read.
FAITH ABOUT ETERNITY
It is never proper to base faith on our improvement after prayer.
To base faith on our improvement after prayer is oftentimes very disappointing.
Oftentimes, very what?
Very disappointing.
"God, give me bread" - and you base your faith on that - the outcome; bread.
If the bread does not come, you will be disappointed.
It works with the will of God and the promise of God; all together.
What is His will?
That is what faith works on.
Is it His will to give you bread, wait a while or not to give you bread?
According to His will we pray; according to His promise we pray.
Jesus prayed that the cup be taken away from Him three times.
"Cup, be taken away from Me."
Another time again, "Cup, be taken away from Me."
Three times.
The prayer of faith can be repeated a thousand times.
This is why the Bible encourages us in 1 Thessalonians 5:16 to pray without ceasing.
It says, prayer without what?
Ceasing.
Prayer without ceasing
because our troubles, challenges and situations are instruments that maintain our union with God.
Tell your neighbour, “My challenges and situations are instruments to maintain my union with God”.
My challenges, I mean, my troubles are instruments to maintain my oneness with God,
to maintain my relationship with God.
But today, the opposite is the case to you.
It is time you begin to see your challenge as a friend.
As Christians, when we pray to God to remove our troubles,
when the troubles are not removed, an equivalent will be provided.
That is why you are here.
This is an equivalent.
That is...
Where God guides, you find yourself
where His grace will be sufficient to protect you while you are going through the problem.
Even though that situation is there, but you are strong in the Lord.
That brought about our relationship.
If not your situation, you would not know me.
If not your situation, I would not know you.
Where will I know you from? A club house?
Where will I know you from? A party?
Where will I know you from?
I would not know you!
You are welcome!
Thank you, sir.
Can you say, "Thank you, my situation"?
Thank you, my situation.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You keep burdening yourself.
You keep being worried, troubled because of your situation.
When situation comes, it is time to grow stronger in the Lord.
As Christians, we must know that our values must be tested against facts and experiences.
Your value must be tested.
You say, "What is my value? How much am I worth?"
If you are no one, nobody will notice, nobody will bother you.
Each time people talk, "T.B. Joshua, T.B. Joshua" - the name is disturbing them.
That is a value.
If I'm no one, nobody will talk about me, nobody will want to attack me or challenge me.
People believe challenging me is making a name for themselves
because of value - what I'm worth.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
People want to write an article in their newspaper, "T.B. Joshua..." - just because they want it to sell.
Look at the Emmanuel TV channel - it is the most watched Christian channel all over the world.
That is the value.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You must know that your values must be tested against facts and experiences.
Tell your neighbour, “My values must be tested against facts and experiences”.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
"No. Why all this?"
Why do you not want to pay a price for your values?
We should ask you, if you truly believe in them, in your values...
Do you believe in them?
The SCOAN Sunday Service
What people say about you; people do this, people hate you, people do that; attack, this and that...
Some of us here are looking for values; they want to create that value for themselves.
You see them when everywhere is quiet,
and in a moment where there is no movement, that is when you see them coming out.
They want people to see them.
That is how they create values for themselves.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
The case of Peter serves as a good example of what we are talking about.
Assume Peter would have caught fish earlier, he would have missed the redemption.
This shows his wasted hours on the sea kept him for a new level in life.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Your sickness can keep you for a new level.
Your disappointment can keep you for a new level.
Failure can keep one for a new level.
Hatred, persecution and temptation can do the same; it will keep you.
You keep saying, "My colleagues are going; see my colleagues - they are there, they are making money,
I don't have a job, joblessness..."
And you don't know that God is keeping you for a new level.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
What are the things you are praying for whose answer seems to delay?
Maybe God wants to keep you for a new level.
Maybe God is keeping or preserving you
to strengthen your desire and your determination for Him.
Ask your neighbour, “What are the things you are praying for whose answer seems to delay?”
Maybe God wants to preserve you.
Maybe God wants to keep you for a new level.
Maybe God wants to strengthen your desire and your determination for Him.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
If you meet any successful person today, they would tell you.
If you meet a wonderful married couple, they would tell you what they went through to be there.
If you meet the person you call your role model today,
they would tell you what it takes to be your role model.
As you count your blessings every day, take time to also count your failures.
There is a school for failure and a school for blessing.
What we are saying has nothing to do with age.
Because you consider your age for everything you do.
It has nothing to do with family; you consider your family in everything you do.
It has nothing to do with education, human natural gift, because you consider all this,
"I'm a graduate, I'm a professor. I have been to this or that place, I have travelled all over the world.
See this man there - he is illiterate and I am a professor."
It has nothing to do with it.
By acting faith, you can only fetch in grace.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Tell your neighbour,
“By acting faith, you can only fetch in grace that will enable you to do what is impossible.”
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You know, I take my time to talk to you.
No!
I really want to talk to you.
Say, “I really want to talk to you”.
That is why you don't see me doing this...
I'm expecting somebody to shout, "Pastor! Hey!", while you are quiet.
I'm expecting to jump, "Yes!"
"Help me to jump, I want to see!" - "Hey!" - "More, more, more!"
You don't need more of this, you just need the one God wants me to give to you.
You keep opening the door God has not opened.
Tell your neighbour, "You keep opening the door God has not opened".
Can you see? This is why many of you are like this.
You keep taking what God has not given you.
You keep opening the door God has not opened.
That is why it is difficult to live long with those things.
At the time you need those things, they are not there for you
because you take it when God has not given you.
Much fame, popularity, wealth has shivered today.
If God has given you, He gives you for the children yet unborn to live and see.
This is why you see our life epileptic today.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
At the time you are not strong, the thing is no longer there.
Tell your neighbour, “We keep taking what God has not given us.
We keep opening the door that God has not opened".
That is, the blessings, wealth and fame of many today.
The joy of the blessing and the fame is to see it when you are no longer living.
Die and leave it behind.
You are not blessed only for this generation but for the generation yet unborn.
If the apostles had died with their achievements, people like me would not be here today.
I’m a partaker of an inheritance of saints.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
So, you can still return what God has no given you and you wait for what God is about to give you.
It is not too late.
Tell your neighbour, “Return what you have not been given and wait for what God is about to give”.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
These are the challenges all over the world.
Not only you; the nation, the continent, the world.
Every aspect of life - marriage, business, career, this and that.
If God has not given you and you take it...
Not that you would not be able to take it - you can take it when God...
The Bible says, "The blessing I give, not as the world gives them".
You can take, even when God has not given you - no problem.
God's time is the best.
I want someone to smile with me, I want someone to smile here.
You are too frowned.
Why are you too frowned?
Let me believe you, you are too frowned.
Smile!
Or you have taken what God has not given you?
Smile, smile, smile.
Oh no, this is not real.
I want that kind of smile.
Let me hear you.
What are you saying there?
You say you will return it?
Yes.
Thank you.
Give thanks to Him.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Such a wonderful time having you around me.
Do you know I love you?
Yes.
How do you know?
How do you know that I love you?
Because I have a question I want to ask you, "How do you know I love you?"
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Do you love me?
Yes!
You love me because you come to the church?
No!
Yes, no worries - time will tell.
Tell your neighbour, "Time will tell".
Do you know what I mean by "time will tell"?
How can you be inside the church and say that you hate me?
You are inside the church and you are looking at me and you say, "I hate you".
It is very difficult; time will tell - when you are out there, we will know.
Time will tell - it is a matter of time.
The question I'm asking is not even relevant.
How can I be looking at you and say, "Love me"; what will I be expecting from you?
Three much!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You have not asked me whether I love you.
No, ask me - I know you know I love you.
Ask me this question.
Do you love us?
OK, you say what?
OK, thank you for loving me.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
That will answer. Thank you for loving me.
Because you say you love me - reciprocate.
If you love me, I love you.
That is it.
That can work.
Oh my God.
Thank you.
- Hallelujah!
- Amen.
May God bless His Word.
Thank You, Lord.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
TT: ROBERT BEGIER 04/07/2018
RV: Mel Flowers 08/07/2018